<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on blogd</title>
    <link>https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on blogd</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 13:44:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HowTO Install Cockpit</title>
      <link>https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/howto-install-cockpit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 13:44:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/howto-install-cockpit/</guid>
      <description>Cockpit is a web based interface that let you manage and monitor different devices.
The installation process is super simple, you just need to install the packet on each device and then you can access with any account that you have.
Main features  Monitoring system activity (CPU, memory, disk IO and network traffics) — System Viewing system log entries — Logs Seeing how full your disk partitions are — Storage Watching networking activity (sent and received) — Networking Taking a look at user accounts — Accounts Checking the status of system services — Services Pulling up information on installed applications — Applications Viewing and installing available updates (if logged in as root) and restart the system if needed — Software Updates Opening and using a terminal window — Terminal  HowTO install Cockpit I&amp;rsquo;m not really going to stop here because it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as doing the installation of the package so use your favorite package manager and do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTO Install Netdata</title>
      <link>https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/howto-install-netdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 21:25:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/howto-install-netdata/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Netdata.
Netdata is a daemon which runs on your device(s) collecting data in real time. It has a very nice interface and it&amp;rsquo;s possible to see your devices from anywhere with Netdata Cloud (once you add your nodes into it).
For monitoring there are a lot of tools which are great like Nagios, Icinga, Prometheus, etc but this one is really easy to install and use from home without doing a lot of stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HowTO Install HUGO</title>
      <link>https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/howto-install-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 23:59:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/howto-install-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Packages that we need
 brew git  Installing HUGO You will need first to have brew installed on your device so make sure that is up and running. Then from linux/mac just open the terminal and install HUGO.
brew install hugo  If everything was fine just check it with:
hugo version  Now a days is common to have git preinstalled by default. Anyway, if you need to check if the package is already there then:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Post</title>
      <link>https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/real-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 19:36:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vanboxen.github.io/posts/real-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome!
The idea behind this blog is to keep track of whatever I&amp;rsquo;m testing at home. I will probably start with how did the setup of HUGO for the blog which is pretty much straight forward to be honest.
Learning curve I really expect to have a huge learning curve just because I&amp;rsquo;ve never done such a thing and also because I&amp;rsquo;m a real &amp;ldquo;test and failure&amp;rdquo; person!
Most common topics  rpi open source packages monitoring NAS NFS SMB Sync the phone on the NAS Big etc!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
